BILLY JOEL VILLANUEVA

WEB DEVELOPER



billy.villanueva.dev@gmail.com

Metro Manila, Philippines

joelvillanueva.dev

EDUCATION

BS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Informatics International College

PROFILE

An experienced web developer from the Philippines. I'm comfortable working across all layers of the web development stack, from the frontend code to the server-side logic. This enables me to work independently or collaboratively within teams.

While my foundation lies in WordPress and PHP, I'm on a journey of expanding my skillset. Currently studying React JS, Python and Artificial Intelligence through online tutorials and by building personal projects.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- HTML/CSS (SCSS/LESS)
- JavaScript, Typescript
- PHP & MySQL
- Python

LIBRARIES & FRAMEWORKS

- WordPress
- Bootstrap
- TailwindCSS
- ReactJS

TOOLS & PLATFORMS

- Git, GitHub
- Atlassian: Jira, Bitbucket
- VS Code
- Trello

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER

Freelance

2020 - Present

• Develop custom websites for clients using Wordpress and Shopify

DEVELOPER

RockSolid Digital

2017-2019

- Develop and maintain Multi-Site Wordpress Websites for various hotels and resorts in Australia: Rydges, Thredbo, Atura, QT Hotels
- Create Custom WP Themes & Plugins, Rest API integrations,
 Mobile apps using Ionic Framework.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Stratpoint Technologies

2016-2017

 Develop a custom Laravel web application for managing business mobile numbers for Globe Telecom.